A Guide to the Papers of Margaret and John Travers Moore, 1914-1994
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence Files (Box 15-23)
  - Publishers - Spoken arts 1989-1991 (Box 20)
  - Q-R Correspondence 1945-1983 (Box 20)
  - Reprints and Permissions 1985-1994, 7 folders (Box 20)
  - Reprints and Permissions 1939-1984, 9 folders (Box 21)
  - The Road (formerly Jingalong) - Correspondence 1987-1991 (Box 21)
  - Royalties 1957-1994, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - George and Peggy Rumberger 1929-1988 (Box 22)
  - S Correspondence 1937-1994 (Box 22)
  - "Sinmin (Lord Elephant)" 1956-1978 (Box 22)
  - Robert Smith and Nancy Mackey (his daughter) 1942-1993 (Box 22)
  - Social Security 1946-1993, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Sports Poems - Correspondence 1983-1987 (Box 22)
  - The Story of Silent Night- Correspondence 1958-1990, n.d., 2 folders (Box 23)
  - T Correspondence 1944-1992 (Box 23)
  - U-Z Correspondence 1936-1993 (Box 23)
  - University of Virginia 1982-1993, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Walt Whitman Center for the Arts and Humanities, Camden, New Jersey 1987-1989 (Box 23)
- Memorabilia & Miscellaneous Material
  - Syracuse University Commencement Booklet 1926, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Date Diary of Margaret Rumberger and John Travers Moore 1927-1929, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Sales Records for A Child's Book of Psalms and Near Centerville 1946-1951, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - "The Symphony" by John Travers Moore, with a foreword by Nathalia Crane, and dedicated to Margaret Moore 1949 Jun 28, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Diary (locked) ca. 1957-1959, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Receipts & Expenses Account Books 1953-1994, Three Bound Volumes (Box 24)
  - Annual from Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio, where Margaret Moore served as a librarian, page 27 1962, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - United Nations Diary, "One Year in the Literary Life of John Travers Moore" 1987, Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Poems by Margaret Moore, some used in Certainly, Carrie, Cut the Caken.d., Bound Volume (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Material
    - Certificates and Awards 1924-1994 (Box 24)
    - Drawings by John Travers Moore and Early Sketches of Robert J. Smith 1931, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Genealogy and Family Histories of John Travers Moore and Margaret Rumberger Moore, with photographs ca. 1919-1994, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Introduction to the Files compiled by John Travers Moore ca. 1984-1994 (Box 25)
    - Memorabilia - Paper 1926-1988, n.d., 2 folders (Box 25)
      for additional memorabilia objects see Box 27
    - Newsclippings 1940-1991 (Box 25)
    - Newsclippings and Press Releases re the Pepito Books and the United Nations 1985-1991, 2 folders, United States & Foreign (Box 25)
    - Philatelic Covers 1928-1938 (Box 25)
    - Photographs ca. 1942-1990 (Box 25)
      also see oversize photograph album for a more complete photographic record of the Moores
    - Plane Facts, published by the Air Service Command 1944-1945 (Box 25)
    - Printed Material 1920-1988 (Box 25)
    - Scrapbook of John Travers Moore's Poems in Periodicals 1931-1984 (Box 26)
    - Scrapbook of Margaret R. Moore's Poems in Periodicals 1939-1988 (Box 26)
    - Scrapbook of Press Releases re Margaret and John Travers Moore 1920-1985, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Stationery by Margaret and John Travers Moore - watercolors n.d. (Box 26)
    - The Traipsin' Woman; Words and Music by John Travers Moore 1966, Printed Copies (Box 26)
    - Trees & Flowers, Two - Pictures & Poems, including "Springburst" by John Travers Moore, produced by Philip Green Educational Limited n.d. (Box 26)
  - Memorabilia Objects
    - The Golden Balloon Award for Outstanding Comtribution to Children, given to Margaret and John Travers Moore for their book Pepito's Speech at the United Nations, the first children's book published by the United Nations 1988 April 24 (Box 27)
    - A Poem by John Travers Moore, "The Other Part," done in needlepoint n.d. (Box 27)
    - A Brass Plate Sign with the name of "Poethaven," the Moore's first home in Hendersonville, North Carolina n.d. (Box 27)
    - A Small Painting of a Nativity Scene on a Piece of Wood n.d. (Box 27)
    - Engraved blocks and an engraved plate reproduction of the bronze sculpture head of John Travers Moore done by Robert J. Smith n.d., 2 items (Box 27)
    - Engraved name plate of John Travers Moore used for engraved stationery n.d. (Box 27)
    - Dry point by Robert J. Smith, reproduced on a block, used as an illustration for A Child's Book of Psalmsn.d. (Box 27)
    - Rose petals from the bridal bouquet of Margaret Rumberger, a ring with a green stone in the setting, a pocketknife, two magnifying glasses & other keepsakes 1928 (Box 27)
    - The Society of Medalists Eighth Issue, 1933, "There is no easy way from the earth to the stars," by Gaetano Cecere (1894-?), sculptor 1933 (Box 27)
    - Certificate of Promotion to the High School, Margaret Rumberger 1917 Jun 15
    - Du Bois High School Diploma, Margaret Rumberger 1921 Jun 2
    - Norwood High School Diploma, John Travers Moore 1926 Jun 11
    - Syracuse University, Bachelor of Science in Library Science, Margaret Rumberger 1926 Jun 14
    - Marriage License of Margaret Rumberger and John Travers Moore, Hamilton County, Ohio 1928 Jun 16
    - Law License of John Travers Moore, State of Ohio 1933 Aug 4
    - Copy of the Marriage License of Margaret and John Travers Moore 1967 Jul 25
    - University of Dayton degree of Juris Doctor, John Travers Moore 1984 Dec 20
    - Posters re Pepito's Speech at the United Nations[ca. 1986]
    - Photograph Album of Margaret and John Travers Moore, "A Pictorial Autobiography ca. 1914-1990
  - Phonographs
    - How Can I Show You God, Jeannette? by John Travers Moore and read by Margaret Moore 1952 Jun 24
    - Radio Station WSAI Interview of Margaret and John Travers Moore, Campus Callboard Program, St. Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio 1954 Dec 11
    - "Let's Listen to a Story" The Three Tripps by Margaret and John Travers Moore, Radio Station WMCA, New York City 1960 May 1
    - Record Album to Accompany Language and How to Use It Book 6, side 2, record 2, the poem "Jet" by John Travers Moore 1969
    - "My Gift is Love" by John Travers Moore and narrated by Ken Linn n.d.
    - "The Cincinnati Waltz" by John Travers Moore, organ solo Helen Gough, vocal by Ray Jogan n.d., 2 copies
  - Cassette Tape Recordings
    - Moore's The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade, Lyrics and Music by Carol Davis and Denise Adams 1985, 2 Cassette Tapes
  - Reel-To-Reel Tape Recordings
    - "Let's Listen to a Story," A radio Program in New York on WMCA, The Three Tripps adridged, also on record 1960 May 1
    - Miscellaneous Poetry Readings and informal gatherings, including Margaret and John Travers Moore, the Marquise de Chambrun, R.J. Smith, John Travers Moore's 59th birthday in 1967 and a radio interview in 1972 ca. 1967-1972
    - The First Moon Landing narrated by John Travers Moore, identifying all voices 1969 Jul 20
    - a) Readings by the Marquise de Chambrun of her poetry and that of Moore b) Radio personality "Farmer Russ" for Station WHVL, Hendersonville, North Carolina, interviews John Travers Moore at "Poethaven" regarding The Story of Silent Night c) Memorabilia, the Moores discuss highlights in their travels in the United States and Europe 1975
    - "My Gift is Love" by John Travers Moore, narrated by Ken Linn n.d.
  - Video Tape Recordings
    - On Common Ground: A Tour of the United Nations, produced by the United Nations, 30 minutes 1987
    - Pepito's Dream A.J. Shalleck Productions, Inc., 27 minutes ca. 1990
    - Americana Calendar Series: Artist--Robert J. Smith & Conversation with Artist Jack Smith, Story by Elmer Webster, Read by Paul Law, Interviewer: Virginia Visser (Produced by Instructional Television, Emporia State University, Kansas [ca. 1994]
  - Sales Records for the literary work of Margaret and John Travers Moore ca. 1939-1983
  - Large Paintings & Other Artwork by Robert J. Smith
    - "John Travers Moore, A Portrait in Bronze" and its pedestal 1942
    - Madonna and Child" n.d.
    - "Autumn" n.d.
    - Untitled Landscape n.d.
    - Framed Pencil Portrait of Margaret Moore n.d.
    - Large Framed Photograph of Margaret Moore n.d.
    - A Watercolor and an oil by John Travers Moore n.d.